Abdulazeez Abioye

Product Designer | UI/UX Designer | UX Researcher olumideabioye@outlook.com | My Portfolio







SUMMARY

I am a versatile professional product designer who plays a crucial role in bringing innovative and functional products to market. I blend creativity with technical expertise to create products that enhance the user experience and meet market demands. I am responsible for creating and designing products that are both functional and aesthetically pleasing.

EXPERIENCE

Parcels Mart — Cumbria, England — *Product Designer*

December 2022 - August 2023

- Partnered with cross-functional teams to align design solutions with business goals, ensuring seamless integrations into logistics services.
- Applied creative expertise to develop innovative solutions, enhancing user experience and reflecting a commitment to transparent pricing and innovation.
- Integrated eco-friendly design principles, reducing environmental impact through initiatives such as eco-packaging and optimized transportation routes.
- Conducted customer research to inform personalized, cost-saving logistics solutions, prioritizing transparent pricing and user satisfaction.
- Designed tailored user interfaces for parcels Mart's diverse global customer base, emphasizing clear and intuitive pricing and service information.

Tools/Technologies - Sketch, Craft, Figma, Anima Toolkit, Slack

Digipipa — Lagos, Nigeria — *UI/UX Designer*

MARCH 2021 - November 2022

- Increased the company website visit volume by 23% by redesigning the website to adapt to mobile devices and incorporating a modern aesthetic through 2+ rounds of sketching.
- Enabled the start-up to monetize with a \$1M estimated return in 2 years by designing the UI/UX of a habit formation iOS app from conception to delivery through 3+ iterations of wireframing, prototyping and user testing.
- Improved the website retention rate by 22% by introducing a stronger design hierarchy that simplifies the user flow for customizing a product.



SKILLS

Tools:

Figma, Sketch, Photoshop, Invision, Sketch, Craft, Prototype.io, XD, Zeplin, Marvel, HTML 5 & CSS

Productivity:

Slack, Trello, Aha, Jira, Clickup, Asana, Notion and more

Soft Skills Set:

Information Architecture, User Research, Wireframing, Usability Testing, Prototyping, Design System, Responsive Web, Inclusive Design, Leadership, Communication, Team Integration, Empathy, Collaboration, Open-mindedness, Critical Thinking, Professionalism, Problem Solving, Adaptability, Accountability, Approachability and many more

PROJECTS

- **DrugStoc Mobile App**
- Digipipa Mobile App
- Parcels Mart
- **ESP Group Landing page** re-design
- Artisan.ng
- Zeli
- **Antique Web3**
- Pay Check limited

 Collaborated with cross-functional teams such as; product managers, developers, and marketers to ensure that the designs align with the company's overall product strategy, meet user needs, and are technically feasible

Tools/Technologies - Figma, Jira, Photoshop, Jira, Slack, Marvel

DrugStoc Ehub Ltd, — Lagos, Nigeria — *Product Designer*

JULY 2019 - FEBRUARY 2022

- Craft intuitive and visually engaging interfaces for DrugStoc Ehub's pharmaceutical solutions, tailored to meet the specific needs of healthcare professionals and stakeholders.
- Continuously enhance user experience on DrugStoc Ehub's digital platforms, emphasizing usability, accessibility, and efficiency to facilitate seamless interactions within the pharmaceutical ecosystem.
- Conduct comprehensive user research, including interviews, surveys, and
 usability tests, leveraging data-driven insights to refine interfaces for peak
 performance. Collaborated closely with cross-functional teams, including
 developers, product managers and healthcare experts ensuring design
 aligns with functionality and business goals.
- Engaged stakeholders for feedback-driven design iterations to meet evolving requirements.

Tools/Technologies - Figma, Photoshop, Invision, Zeplin, Craft

Others Includes:

Hayzed Poultry, Ilorin, Nigeria — Visual Artist

February 2018 - February 2021.

Tools/Technologies - Corel Draw, Photoshop.

CERTIFICATION

Principles of UX/UI Design

Meta (Formerly Facebook)

<u>UI/UX Design Hybrid from Figma to</u> <u>HTML CSS and JavaScript</u> **Udemy**

EDUCATION

User Research and Design JANUARY 2024 University of Minnesota

Prototyping and Design JANUARY 2024 University of Minnesota

University of Ilorin, SEPTEMBER 2018-2022 Msc: in Sociology